Inventory of Civil registers of actions from District Court (Seventh District: Carbon County), 1896-1987.
Utah State Archives and Records Service
District Court (Seventh District: Carbon County) Civil registers of actions
1896-1987.
Utah State Archives and Records Service 300 South Rio Grande Salt Lake City, UT 84101-1182 801-533-3535 historyresearch@utah.gov
Series 14182
District Court (Seventh District: Carbon County)
13 microfilm reels
Registers of action contain notations for documents filed in a civil case.
Civil cases document the legal process and the administration of justice in conjunction with civil proceedings for the determination of a controversy between parties wherein rights are enforced or protected, or wrongs are prevented or redressed. Records and documents pertaining to a particular civil action are filed together by the court clerk and collectively these documents constitute the case file. As these records or actions are filed, the clerk enters them in the registers which comprise this series. The clerk is required as documents enter the case file to make a notation that shows "the nature of each paper filed or writ issued and the substance of each order or judgment of the court and of the returns showing execution of process. The notation of an order or judgment shall show the date the notation is made. When trial by jury has been properly demanded or ordered the clerk shall enter the word "jury" on the page assigned to that action [UCA 79 (b) (2)]."
A register of actions may contain the following entries for each civil case: name of the attorney for plaintiff and defendant, name of the judge presiding over the case, petitions, complaints, summons, answers to summons, orders from the court, assignment of judges, exhibits, judgment, findings and conclusions, costs, decrees, requests by attorneys for instructions to the jury, verdict, motions for cross complaints or new trials, amendments to previous answers and disclaimers.
Research Note
Researchers should consult this series to ensure finding all the actions which occurred in a case. After July 1, 1987, further logging of actions is done elsewhere in court records.
Numerical by case number, thereunder chronological
This series is classified as Public.
These records were acquired from the creating agency through established retention schedules.
Minute books from the District Court (Seventh District: Carbon County), Series 14180, documents the proceedings of each case.
Civil case files from the District Court (Seventh District: Carbon County), Series 84954, contains the entire case file listed in these registers.
Politics, Government, and Law; Civil Procedure and Courts
Divorce suits--Carbon County (Utah).; Corporate divestiture--Utah--Carbon County.; Judgments--Utah--Carbon County.
Carbon County (Utah)--Trials (Divorce).; Carbon County (Utah)--Actions and defenses--Cases.; Carbon County (Utah)--Habeas corpus.
- Civil registers of actions, 1896-1987.; 13 microfilm reels
  - 1-471, 1896-1909 (Reel 1, Volume 1)
  - 472-949, 1909-1915 (Reel 1, Volume 2)
  - 950-1545, 1915-1920 (Reel 2, Volume 3)
  - 1546-2179, 1920-1923 (Reel 2, Volume 4)
  - 2180-2816, 1923-1926 (Reel 3, Volume 5)
  - 2817-3447, 1926-1929 (Reel 3, Volume 6)
  - 3448-4092, 1929-1933 (Reel 4, Volume 7)
  - 4093-4744, 1933-1937 (Reel 4, Volume 8)
  - 4745-5394, 1937-1943 (Reel 5, Volume 9)
  - 5395-6042, 1943-1947 (Reel 5, Volume 10)
  - 6043-6682, 1947-1950 (Reel 6, Volume 11)
  - 6683-7334, 1950-1954 (Reel 6, Volume 12)
  - 7335-7984, 1954-1958 (Reel 7, Volume 13)
  - 7985-8635, 1958-1962 (Reel 7, Volume 14)
  - 8636-9285, 1962-1966 (Reel 8, Volume 15)
  - 9286-9935, 1966-1971 (Reel 8, Volume 16)
  - 9936-10585, 1971-1975 (Reel 9, Volume 17)
  - 10586-11235, 1975-1977 (Reel 9, Volume 18)
  - 11236-11835, 1977-1978 (Reel 10, Volume 19)
  - 11836-12435, 1978-1980 (Reel 10, Volume 20)
  - 12436-13035, 1980-1981 (Reel 11, Volume 21)
  - 13036-13635, 1981-1983 (Reel 11, Volume 22)
  - 13636-14235, 1983-1984 (Reel 12, Volume 23)
  - 14236-14835, 1984-1986 (Reel 12, Volume 24)
  - 14836-15288, 1986-1987 (Reel 13, Volume 25)